

CURRICULUM VITAE

Name : Mohammed Saifur Rahman

Contact Address: 108 Lalbagh Road, Dhaka-1211, Bangladesh

Telephone No. : 01610001178(Mobile), 02-9630345 (Res)

E-mail : saifur.rahman1178@gmail.com

Profile : A skilled organizer and communicator with extensive experience of dealing

with general people. Competent and efficient at handling numerous tasks simultaneously. Hardworking, conscientious and capable to take responsibility and committed to work on own initiative and work as part of a team. Good analytical and dispute resolution skills. Dedicated to maintain high quality

standards.

Objective: Intend to work in a challenging and competitive environment, where sense of

responsibility and commitment is required, the dignity of work provides job

satisfaction and the place of work provides potential avenue for learning. Work

for interest, innovation for excellence and pleasure.

Educational Qualification:

Degree: Masters of Business Administration (MBA)

Major : Marketing Year of Completion : 2002

Class: With Distinction

Institution: University of Lincolnshire, UK.

Degree: Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

Major: Finance
Year of Completion: 1999
Grades: CGPA 3.18

Institution: Independent University Bangladesh.

Degree : Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

Group: Science
Year of Completion: 1994
Grades: 1st division

Institution: Govt. Science Collage. Dhaka Board.

Degree: Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Group: Science
Year of Completion: 1991
Grades: 1st division

Institution: Wills Little Flower School, Dhaka Board.

Work Experience

Organization:

Genex Infosys Limited

Address:

Nitol Niloy Tower (Level 6-12), Nikunja C/A, Airport Road, Dhaka

Position:

Manager, Quality Assurance

Duration:

19 February, 2018 to 31 December, 2019

Achievements:

After three months of joining in Robi inbound process I have given the responsibility of Robi Outbound, Telesales, Digital Channel and 333(Government) process.

Major Responsibilities :

- Maintain call quality score in day-to-day basis in order to ensure optimal service delivery for inbound, outbound and Tele sales.
- Monitoring skill wise repeat percentage and ensure that the repeat percentage is within target.
- Monitoring Line of Business (LOB) wise customer satisfaction score (ICE) on a day to day basis and ensure that the customer satisfaction score increased day by day.
- Analyzing CQC wise ICE score and take necessary action to improve ICE Score where low.
- Consistently monitor the performance of Auditors and ensure that they are maintaining KPI.
- Error free reporting to the management.
- Follow up with the concerned regarding any assigned task with the management.
- Conducting calibration session (internal & external) and assured that the calibration score is within the benchmark.
- Prepare presentation for weekly, monthly and quarterly review with the client and internal and present those in the in the meeting.
- Doing analysis on parameter wise QA score, repeat and ICE and share findings with the management on a weekly and monthly basis
- Recommendation for TNA where and when required.
- Arranging contest for Agents and TLs on a monthly basis to ensure superior customer experience.
- Efficacy report and shift briefing and training on a regular basis

Organization:

Airtel Bangladesh Ltd. (Former Warid Telecom)

Address:

23/3 Khilji Road, Shayamoli, ASA Tower, Dhaka-1207

Position:

Compliance & Audit Manager, Service Quality, Customer Service

Duration:

September 26, 2006 to November 08, 2016

Achievements:

I have joined Warid Telecom now Airtel as a supervisor, Quality Assurance in grade 1.3. After six months, based on my performance, dedication and motivation I have been positioned to grade 2.1 with a reasonable raise in my salary. In next appraisal I have been promoted as a Senior Executive with grade 2.2. By the middle of 2011 I have been promoted as Compliance and Audit Manager with the responsibility to manage a team of 10 members and with the full responsibilities of compliance and audit activities.

Major Responsibilities:

- Determining key improvement areas Vs performance gap analysis by auditing calls, task, e-mails& callback to walk in customers, generate reports, improvement tracking and perform TNA (Training Need Assessment) for training team on a regular basis
- Ensuring the BTRC regulatory requirements is properly followed from filling-up all sorts of documentation (RF, SIM Replacement, IR, SIU) till archival.
- Ensuring all interactions are monitored effectively to identify areas of non compliance with laid down policies and standards
- Maintaining and monitoring major KPIs in terms of CSMM, ICE & FCR.
- Monitoring& provides feedback on VAS & Data up-sell, 777 security checks, Live call & DOB OB campaign calls.
- Close loop monitoring of agents & segmentation through bucketization process.
- Coordination with other departments for the simulation of product / system/ policies
- Develop action plans to improve/correct performance for the team members and keep them motivated to perform their best with maximum job satisfaction.
- Ensuring appropriate corrective action is planned, implemented and monitoring the effectiveness of the actions
- Support Contact Experience, AEC, ARC and ASC to improve upon the quality of service to airtel customers.
- Mystery survey to all AECs and ARCs on a Quarterly Basis and provide Report accordingly
- Participate in cross departmental projects with other CS departments for achieving set goals.
- Ensure that the audit mechanism and methodology truly reflects the 'as-is' customer perception & Voice.
- To build good relationships with stakeholders and utilize these relationships to ensure successful outcomes that adds credibility and value to the reputation and strategic aims of Airtel.

Worked as a project coordinator in Robi-Airtel Merger Project: (May 16, 2016 to November 05, 2016)

- Align all Customer Services processes of Robi and airtel for the merged-co scenario. (Align 64 processes and top 20 Standard Operating Procedures)
- Drive Net Promoter System (NPS) both top-down and bottom-up as well as the service quality improvement initiatives across the organization.
- Improvement/execute quality assurance checks and audits (Service Excellence Audit) as part of the service improvement framework.
- Define the service delivery standard as per industry best practices and global service benchmark.
- Ensure effective use of quality assurance tools, techniques and findings
- Analyze and identify the area of improvements and strength from various quality measurement tools/surveys/research (NPS, C-SAT, etc.).

• Arrange workshops/meetings with relevant stakeholders (internal and business partners) for setting action plans to enhance the quality of service and also to improve NPS)

Organization:

Address:

Position:

Duration:

Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia, Dhaka Study Center

House 55, Road 4A, Dhanmondi, Dhaka-1209, Bangladesh.

Deputy General Manager (DGM)

February 2002 to September 25, 2006

Achievements:

I have joined BETS on February 11, 2002 as a Senior Executive. Just after six months based on the evaluation of my performance the management has given me the responsibility of a Manager, BETS Education (BE). From September 1, 2003 I have been promoted as Deputy General Manager (DGM) of the same organization and of BVL on deputation from BETS Education with the same rank, status and privileges and has given me the supervisory role of all the staff members of BVL and BE.

Major Responsibilities:

- Developing and maintaining system for smooth functioning of financial and administrative activities in compliance with organization's policy practice and procedure.
- Initiate and finalizes all establishment matters of the companies such as employee recruitment, positioning, discipline and the training for the new employees.
- Supervise the work/ activities of all the employees of the company including performance planning, monitoring, giving feedback, review, evaluation and development of large numbers of employees of different disciplines.
- Preparation of action plan, supervision and monitoring on achievement in timely manner with proper coordination among the concern departments/units.
- Arrangement of events like seminars, workshops, training etc.
- Arrange all types of logistic support to conduct IELTS test under IDP.
- Financial planning including budgeting using appropriate method, tools and approaches.
- Checking legitimate papers in approval process.
- Fund management; keeping liquid money available at optimum level.
- Counseling students who would like to enroll directly in Melbourne campuses
- Visa consultation for Melbourne going students.
- Attending meetings and workshops conducted by the Australian High Commission.
- Conducting smooth participations in different international education fair.
- Directly monitoring all sorts of marketing activities like inserting advertisement to the daily newspaper, organizing PR activities, preparing and updating of promotional materials (Brochure, leaflets, posters, banners, CDs etc), sending direct mail to various customer group on a regular basis, performance of Industry Link Unit(ILU) members to be hired on a time to time basis, corporate presentation throughout the year as part of ongoing marketing activities, conduct

market research and gathering market intelligence on an ongoing basis.

Organization:

OnVocation.com

Address:

145-147 St John Street, SW16, London, UK.

Position:

Market Representative (Project work)

Duration:

1 July, 2000 to 31 August, 2000

Commitment:

Working as part of dynamic team with high standard quality of marketing strategy and marketing research. Highly motivated sales professional to play a key role in developing and growing online career centre business.

Major Responsibilities:

- Worked on online marketing and sales department.
- Major part of my duties is focusing client's concern about online banking and financial recruitment community.
- Helping to develop and integrate new advertising and promotional features on the website.
- Conducting all sorts of marketing activities like inserting advertisement to the daily newspaper, organizing PR activities, preparing and updating of promotional materials (leaflets, posters, banners, CDs etc).
- Corporate presentation to the corporate clients as part of ongoing marketing activities.
- Conducting market research and gathering market intelligence on an ongoing basis.

Organization:

GSS International

Address:

127/A Kawran Bazar, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Position:

Marketing Executive

Duration:

January 1999 to August 1999

Commitment:

Highly motivated marketing professional to play a key role in developing and growing medical equipment and medical gas pipeline business.

- Major Responsibilities:
- Worked in marketing and sales department.
- Major part of my duties is to deal with customers and handle customers complain and ensure after sales service.
- Conducting market research and gathering market intelligence on an ongoing basis.
- Conduct direct marketing to the corporate clients using the pull strategy concept and corporate presentation as part of ongoing marketing activities.
- Sending direct mail to various customer groups on a regular basis.
- Dealing with tenders and also helping to prepare tender documents.
- Supervising and monitoring the team of 5 people in absence of Marketing Manager.
- Member of the employee recruitment and development committee.

Organization:

BOC Bangladesh Limited

Address:

Tejgaon Commercial Area, Dhaka 1011, Bangladesh.

Position:

Intern

Duration:

September 1998 to December 1998

Commitment:

Worked as a part of dynamic project based team with high standard and quality market research to increase the customer satisfaction level.

Major Responsibilities:

- Worked in marketing and sales department.
- Major part of my duties is to make invoices for different projects and to deal with tenders.
- Conducting market research and gathering market intelligence on an ongoing basis.
- Member of a team to prepare accounts manual and financial policy for the company.
- Done a research project and have deliver a report on customer satisfaction and the products and services offered by BOC Bangladesh Ltd."BOC Bangladesh Limited an Invisible Fabrics of Life".

Research Experience:

Has done a research work on "BOC Bangladesh Limited and Customer Satisfaction an Analysis" Dissertation; MBA Program: University of Lincolnshire; Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Philip Tether, Department of Marketing, University of Lincoln; March 2001 to October 2001.

Other Courses/Trainings:

- Successfully attended two days "Excel Leadership Excellence" workshop held on December 17-18, 2012 at BRAC CDMA Savar, Dhaka; organized by Airtel Bangladesh Limited, developed and conducted by HR Kites.
- Successfully attended two days "Public Speaking & Presentation Skill" training program held on November 16-17, 2011 at ASA Tower, Dhaka; organized by Airtel Bangladesh Limited, developed and conducted by HR Kites.
- Attended one month "Certificate Course in Personnel Management" –
 June 01, 1999 to July 08 1999 conducted by Bangladesh Institute of
 Management (BIM).
- Attended a day long CV writing workshop as a facilitator conducted by Prof. G M Chowdhury and Dr. Tanvir A Khan – March 10, 2004 – Organized jointly by Independent University Bangladesh (IUB), Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia and Rotary Club of Dhaka West.

Seminar Attended / Organized :

- Seminar on "Impact of Recent Security Measures on International Supply Chains"; January 12, 2004;Organized & Sponsored by: Victoria University, Melbourne, Dhaka Study Centre, Dhaka; Resource person: Dr. Shams Rahman, Director, Logistics Management Industry Program, Institute of Transport Studies, The University of Sydney, Australia.
- Seminar on "Findings of National Enterprise Survey in Bangladesh",
 September 22, 2003, Ball Room, Dhaka Sheraton Hotel, Organized
 by: International Consulting Group (ICG) Australia in association
 with MIDAS & HB Consultants Bangladesh; Sponsored by: DFID,
 USAID, SDC&Sida.
- Seminar on "Corporate Governance Should We Regulate Corporations and How?"; August 11, 2003; Organized & Sponsored by: Victoria University, Melbourne, Dhaka Study Centre, Dhaka; Resource person: Prof. Geoffrey George, School of Accounting and Finance, Faculty of Business & Law, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.
- Seminar on "Cross-cultural Communication in Business"; July 22, 2003; Organized & Sponsored by: Victoria University, Melbourne, Dhaka Study Centre, Dhaka; Resource person: Dr. Fran Siemensma, Faculty of Business & Law, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.
- Seminar on "The Balance Scorecard Turning Theory into Reality"; July 31, 2002; Organized & Sponsored by: Victoria University, Melbourne, Dhaka Study Centre, Dhaka; Resource person: Mr. Peter Demediuke, CPA, Course Director of the Masters of Business in Finance, School of Accounting and Finance, Faculty of Business & Law, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia; Visiting faculty of the University of Gutenberg, Sweden.
- Seminar on "20 / 20 Vision Clarifying Strategy"; July 20, 2002;
 Organized & Sponsored by: Victoria University, Melbourne, Dhaka
 Study Centre, Dhaka; Resource person: Mr. Mark Wainwright,
 Faculty of Business & Law, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia
 and a Fellow of The Institute of Motor Industries.

Computer Skills:

- Hands on work experience on Microsoft Office Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power point, Microsoft Access.
- Hands on work experience on software installation, uploading, downloading, internet browsing, trouble shooting.

Language	Skills	:
----------	--------	---

	Speaking	Writing	Reading	Listening
English	Good	Good	Good	Good
Bengali	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent

Interests:

Gardening, playing cricket and table tennis, traveling and collecting crystal decoration pieces.

Personal Information:

Father's Name : Dr. Mohammed Akram
Mother's Name : Mrs. Hamida Akram
Date of Birth : September 26, 1976
Nationality : Bangladeshi
Marital Status : Married
Family Status : Two daughters
Religion : Muslim (Sunni)

Certification:

I hereby certify that, to the best of my knowledge and brief, these data correctly describe me, my qualification and my experience.

Authorized Signature:

Mohammed Saifur Rahman

Hahman .